{
  "cards": [
    {
      "question": "What is the regex wildcard character?",
      "answer": "The wildcard character is a dot (.)",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the regex character representing zero or more occurrences of the preceding character?",
      "answer": "The asterisk (*)",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the regex character representing one or more occurrences of the preceding character?",
      "answer": "The plus sign (+)",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the regex character representing zero or one occurrence of the preceding character?",
      "answer": "The question mark (?)",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you represent a literal period (.) in a regex?",
      "answer": "\\.",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you represent a literal backslash (\\) in a regex?",
      "answer": "\\\\",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What placeholder signifies the beginning of a string?",
      "answer": "^",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What placeholder signifies the end of a string?",
      "answer": "$",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you represent the characters a through z in a regex?",
      "answer": "[a-z]",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you represent any one of the characters in the set a, b, or c in a regex?",
      "answer": "[abc]",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you match any set of characters not contained in the range a through d in a regex?",
      "answer": "[^a-d]",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you match any set of characters not in the set a, b, or c in a regex?",
      "answer": "[^abc]",
      "category": "regex",
      "level": 1
    }
  ]
}
